# **Amandeep Singh**

DevOps specialist with ample experience in financial, trading, and non-profit sectors. Throughout my career, I was privileged to work with skilled people in multiple realms, and elite projects, including Delta Airlines, Football Pools, VAKT, Credit Suisse, et cetera.

#### Experience

Oracle (Jan 2020 - Working)

State Street: (April 2019 - Dec 2020)

- Implemented a complete CI/CD solution for an internal Application from scratch using ConcourseCI.
- Enabled a team in Artefacts management and Deployment on Kubernetes.
- Enabled a blockchain initiative at State Street from the DevOps perspective.
- Implemented an Enterprise level observability stack including EFK, Prometheus-Grafana, Open Tracing running on Kubernetes.

ThoughtWorks: (Jan 2015 - April 2019)

- Helped in Automation of the calabash test suite for the Delta airlines.
- Worked on a betting platform product with ~25 micro-services written in Ruby on Rails deployed using Vagrant and Puppet.
- Worked on a hospitality business in creating their multiple UI's/single backend platform for all their franchise brands.
- Worked on an internal platform of an investment bank to manage their Gift and Entertainment services.
- Worked and enabled a first-class blockchain platform Vakt from DevOps side.
- Worked end-to-end on an internal Application [Ramp up] of Thoughworks starting from analysis till deployment.

### Technical Experience

Proficient In: AWS, CI/CD, Observability, Terraform, Linux/Unix, Problem Solving, Concourse

CI, Jaeger, Git

Experienced With:

Backend: Java, Ruby on Rails, Spring boot, JUnit, Jasmine, Rspec, Cucumber

DevOps: Ruby, Golang, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, TCP/IP stack, Information

Security, GOCD.

Telemetry: EFFK Stack, Open Tracing.

Others: Data structures, Algorithms

**Open Source** Please visit my **Github** profile for my side projects, and

**Open Source contributions** 

#### **Certifications**

**2020-2023** Certified kubernetes Administrator; Linux Foundation

Credentials: LF-ipxdcfqgi3

## Education

**2019-2020** Post Graduate Diploma, Information Security; IGNOU (Delhi)

**Project title:** Security implementation in CI/CD using Concourse

**2011-2015** B.Tech, Computer Science and Engineering; GNDU (Amritsar)

Amandeep11121993@gmail.com • +91-9803972479 • Principal DevOps Engineer Bangalore, India